Cabot, Richard C. (Richard Clarke), 1868-1939. Papers of Richard Clarke Cabot: an inventory
Harvard University Archives
Papers of Richard Clarke Cabot, 1886-1974 (inclusive), 1888-1939 (bulk)
Harvard University Archives
HUG 4255.xx
ca. 255 boxes
Richard Clarke Cabot (1868-1939) was a physician and medical educator whose interests included social work, religion and medicine, and medical ethics. The Papers of Richard Clarke Cabot document both his professional and family life.
This document last updated 2006 August 23.
Related Materials
Social ethics seminary [i.e. "seminar," transcript], October 11, 1926 / [speakers] James Ford, Richard C. Cabot, Sheldon Glueck, William W. Fenn, and William Thomas Ham (HUC 8926.282) and other materials by or about Richard Clarke Cabot cataloged in Harvard's online library information system, HOLLIS.
Records of the various schools, hospitals, and departments in which Richard Clarke worked.
Overall Organization of the Collection
The first project processed 126 containers. These materials are referred to collectively as Correspondence and other papers, 1886-1939. The second project processed 129 containers. There is no collective name for this material. It is instead organized into the following series: Biographical Material, Correspondence, Writings, Teaching Material, Lectures of Professor Rosenstock-Huessy, and Medical Records.
Restrictions
Restrictions on access to the collection apply. Portions of the collection are closed. Contact Harvard University Archives Reference staff for details.
Biography of Richard Clarke Cabot
Richard Clarke Cabot (1868-1939) was a physician and medical educator whose interests included social work, religion and medicine, and medical ethics. He taught at Harvard University, where his courses were in the fields of clinical medicine, philosophy, and social ethics, from 1902 until 1934. He practiced at Massachusetts General Hospital from 1898 until 1921.
Cabot was born on May 21, 1868 in Brookline, Massachusetts. He was the fifth son of James Elliot and Elizabeth (Dwight) Cabot. He attended the Nobel and Greenough School after which he attended Harvard. He received his A.B. degree summa cum laude in 1889 and his M.D. in 1892. On October 26, 1894, Cabot married Ella Lyman (1866-1934).
He started his medical career at Massachusetts General Hospital and continued as a member of the consulting staff there until his death. He was also a consultant to the New England Hospital for Women and Children, the Westboro School for Boys, and the Lancaster School for Girls. He was an army doctor on the hospital ship Bay State in the Spanish-American War and at a base hospital in France during World War I.
He was a maverick in the medical field, favoring socialized medicine and founding a department of medical social work at Massachusetts General Hospital in 1905. He also created the teaching method known as the clinicopathological conference (C.P.C.).
Cabot's teaching career spanned nearly four decades. At Harvard, he was Lecturer on Philosophy (1902-1903), Instructor in Clinical Medicine (1903-1908), Assistant Professor of Clinical Medicine (1908-1913), Assistant Professor of Medicine (1913-1918), Professor of Clinical Medicine (1918-1933), and Professor of Social Ethics (1920-1934). From 1935 to 1939, he was professor of natural theology at the Andover-Newton Theological School.
Cabot's earliest writings were on blood, serum, and physical diagnosis. His clinical studies resulted in a series of famous medical books including Physical Diagnosis, Case Histories in Medicine, and Differential Diagnosis. His later writings were on ethics and include What Men Live By, The Meaning of Right and Wrong, and Adventures on the Borderland of Ethics.
He belonged to many professional organizations, including the American Academy of Arts and Sciences, the Association of American Physicians, the American Medical Association, the Massachusetts Medical Society,; Sigma Xi, and the National Conference of Social Work, of which he was president in 1930. Cabot received various honors throughout his career, including the gold medal of the National Institute of Social Sciences (1931) and three honorary degrees, an LL.D. (Rochester, 1930), an L.D.H. (Syracuse, 1934) and a D.D. (Colby, 1938).
He died on May 7, 1939 in Cambridge, Massachusetts.
Scope of the Richard Clarke Cabot Papers
This collection documents both Cabot's professional life and his family life. A large subseries documents the efforts of Ada P. McCormick to produce a biography of Cabot.
Cabot's professional interests are reflected in medical records, teaching materials, writings, and speeches. These records document his practice of medicine, his interest in social medicine, medical ethics and religion, and the teaching of both clinical and social aspects of medicine.
Personal, family, and biographical material consists of both original documents, such as diaries, photographs, and correspondence, and research notes and manuscripts, such as Ada McCormick's interviews with family and friends and drafts of portions of the biography she began to write.
Overview of Series and Subseries in the Collection
Material described 1977-1978
Correspondence and Other Papers, ca. 1886-1939. HUG 4255
Biographical Material (25 containers)
Correspondence (21 containers)
Teaching Notes (65 containers)
General File (8 containers)
Notes of Speeches (4 containers)
Material arranged and described 1997. VARIOUS CALL NUMBERS
Biographical Materials (25 containers) Includes Ada B. McCormick research for a biography of Cabot.
Correspondence (22 containers)
Writings (20 containers)
Teaching material (3 boxes)
Lectures of Professor Rosenstock-Huessy (1 box)
Medical Case Records (62 containers)
Provenance
Bequest of Ada P. McCormick, and gifts of Andrew Dodds, Richard Hocking, Arthur Linenthal, and Schlesinger Library.
Accession numbers:
7644,
7682,
7835,
9170,
9324,
9356,
9382
- Correspondence and other papers, ca. 1886-1939, HUG 4255
  Series Titles and Box Numbers
  Biographical Material:
  Boxes 1-25
  Correspondence:
  Boxes 26-46
  Teaching Notes:
  Boxes 47-101
  General File:
  Boxes 102-119
  Notes of Speeches:
  Boxes 120-124
  - Biographical Material
    - Diaries, Notes, Address Books, Guest Books, and Photograph Album
      - Important Dates since 1894 (Box Box 1)
      - Miscellaneous fragments (Box Box 1)
      - Readings by RCC (Box Box 1)
      - Notebook 1894 and European Trip, 1894: Vol. I (Box Box 1)
      - Items inserted into above notebook. (Box Box 1)
      - Notebook 1894 and European Trip, 1894: Vol. II (Box Box 1)
      - Items inserted into above notebook. (Box Box 1)
      - Notes on Dr. Cabot's illness January 6-May 7, 1939; notes on Mrs. Cabot's illness by RCC, September 1934 (Box Box 1)
      - Funeral Service (Box Box 1)
      - Miscellaneous notes and fragments (Box Box 1)
      - Personal (Box Box 1)
      - Books which have influenced me (R.C.C.) (Box Box 1)
      - Reprint from The Development of Harvard University since the inauguration of President Eliot 1869-1929, ed. Samuel Eliot Morison (Box Box 2)
      - Data regarding the life of RCC, with one sheet containing pencilled data in his own handwriting (Box Box 2)
      - Western War Trip, December to March 1916-1917 (Box Box 2)
      - RCC Notebook, February 1925-February 1926 (Box Box 2)
      - Degree (Colby College 1938, Honorary) and photos (Box Box 2)
      - Diary, 1888 (Box Box 3)
      - Journal of the Western Trip, 1901 (Box Box 3)
        Also, last of the European trips, October, 1930, in end of book.
      - Notes in Philosophical Conferences and inserts (Box Box 3)
      - Notebook [Discussions on Philosophical Subjects, 1902-1903] and inserts (Box Box 3)
      - Notebook on Cruise, 1934 (Box Box 3)
      - Photos and drawings from Cruise Notebook, 1934 (Box Box 3)
      - Notebook The Test of the Prophets, Balance, Sources of Enthusiasm, Relation of Long Jobs and Short Jobs (Box Box 3)
      - Founders of the RCC Educational Fund, (Bound volume) (Box Box 3)
      - Inserts from above item: Letters and an address (on Presence, by RCC)
      - European Trip, Summer of 1928 (Box Box 3)
      - Ella Lyman, Philosophy 2 (course) paper (Box Box 3)
      - RCC '89: Philosophy 13 Mid-Year (Box Box 3)
      - Diary, 1932-1934 (Box Box 4)
      - Guest Book, Cohasset, 1909-1922 (Box Box 4)
      - Address Book and inserts (Box Box 4)
      - Party Book, Northeast Harbor, 1929-1937 (Box Box 4)
      - Birthday Book and inserted letter, 1935 (Box Box 4)
      - Northeasterly Log and inserts, 1935-1937 (Box Box 4)
      - Guest Book, Cohasset, and inserts, including some photographs, 1920-1932 (Box Box 4)
      - Notebook containing recipes, with inserts, [1892] (Box Box 10)
      - Notebook: Second European Trip, 1908 (Box Box 10)
      - Diary 1883 (Box Box 10)
      - Notebook: Medical Notes (Box Box 10)
      - Notebook: Diary (partial) 1885 (Box Box 10)
      - Notebook: Address Book (Paris), 1917-1918 (Box Box 10)
      - Harvard Athletics: 2 Scrapbooks, 1883-1884 (Box Box 11)
      - Album of snapshots at Cohasset and Waltham (Box Box 11)
      - Scrapbook notes and sketches by Catharine I. Fraser (Box 21)
      - Cabot Material (Box 22)
      - Cabot Pictures - Property of Margaret Riley, R.N. (Box 22)
      - [Notes] (Box 21)
    - American Expeditionary Force
      - Mock medal, "Chevalier de la Legion Du Fou Rire" (Box Box 5)
      - Lt. Col, Cabot, A.E.F. [American Expeditionary Force]: Commission, discharge, etc., 1917-1919 (Box Box 5)
      - Lt. Col. Cabot, A.E.F.: Personal Reports, Travel Orders, etc., 1917-1919 (Box Box 5)
      - Notes and Documents on France, 1917-1919 (Box Box 5)
      - Receipted Bills: France, 1917-1919 (Box Box 5)
      - Notes of RCC's trip to the British Front, Oct. 1917 (Box Box 5)
      - Book I: Notes on `Flu' Epidemic Base Hospital No. 6 A.E.F., 1918 (Box Box 5)
      - Notes on Emphysema: Bordeaux, 1917-1918 (Box Box 5)
      - Clinical Notes and Autopsies: France, 1917-1919 (Box Box 5)
      - Copies of Monthly Reports, Base Hospital No. 6 A.E.F. 1917-1919 (Box Box 5)
      - Miscellaneous papers relating to service in A.E.F. (Box Box 5)
      - Miscellaneous papers 1917-1919: newspaper clippings, magazine article by RCC, some photos and postcards, Red Cross Bulletin (Box Box 5)
      - Notes of speech by RCC at the Reunion of Base Hospital No. 6, March 18, 1939 (Box Box 5)
      - Old programs with a sketch by RCC of Base Hospital No. 6 (Box Box 5)
      - Photographs: Base Hospital No. 6. A.E.F. (Box Box 5)
    - Personal Calendars
      - 1907-1917 (Box Box 6)
      - 1918-1929 (Box Box 7)
      - 1930-1939 (Box Box 8)
        Includes article from N.Y. Herald Tribune, October, 1938 re: RCC talk on group medicine
      - Appointment and Note Books, 1891-1939 and undated (Box Box 9)
    - Philosophy, Ethics, and Religion
      - Early notes on philosophy and ethics (Box Box 14)
      - RCC's examination papers in Philosophy 4, History 101887-1889 (Box Box 14)
      - [Daily Themes] 1885-1886 (Box Box 14)
      - College Themes 1886-1887 (Box Box 14)
      - [RCC paper for Royce course]: Certainty, 1901 (Box Box 14)
      - Questionnaire on Deception and Juvenile Delinquency, 1897 (Box Box 14)
      - Bishop Blougram's Apology, First Forensic, 1889 (Box Box 14)
      - RCC thesis in criticism of Royce's ethical philosophy (Box Box 14)
      - Josiah Royce MSS.: 1) Some Social Aspects of Mental Therapeutics, 39 pp.; 2) Critical Rejoinders, 7 pp. (a reply to RCC's criticism of Royce) (Box Box 14)
      - RCC: Theses in philosophy (Box Box 14)
      - Philosophy 4 paper by Anne Hallowell, '93 (Box Box 14)
      - Miscellaneous notes: RCC and others (Box Box 15)
      - RCC notes on religion (Box Box 15)
      - Josiah Royce Ms.: Lecture to the Philosophy 20c class, May 11, 1903 (a proposed course in logic) (Box Box 16)
      - Truth Speaking (second paper) (Box Box 16)
      - Concepts Clustering about Infinity (Box Box 16)
      - Definition,1899 (Box Box 16)
      - Address: Episcopal Church, Cohasset, July 25, 1915 (Box Box 16)
      - What is Involved in Earnestness, 1910 (Box Box 16)
      - Notes on Christianity, Ann Arbor, November 1914 (Box Box 16)
      - Sunday, March 7, 1915: Buffalo (Box Box 16)
      - Failure of Substitutes for Christianity, Church of the Disciples, Boston; Washington's Birthday, 1921 (Box Box 16)
      - Form, Appleton Chapel, February 20, 1915 (Box Box 16)
      - "Rules of the Game" (discussion, good methods of), 1902-1903 (Box Box 16)
      - W.E. Hocking on R.C.C.'s book (Aug. 11, 1933) (Box Box 16)
      - Foreword from Dicks' book. (Box Box 16)
      - Notes on Books IV-VI of Augustine's Confessions (Box Box 16)
      - Fact and Duty (Box Box 16)
      - Veracity: notes and correspondence, 1903-1907 (Box Box 16)
      - Certainty, Immortality, Religious Education (Box Box 16)
      - The Exception that Creates and Sustains (Box Box 16)
      - The Need of Reform in the Conception of Morality usually held by Reformers (Box Box 16)
      - S.E.A. -Emerson's Self-Reliance (Box 22)
      - Notes on J. Royce's Lectures in Philosophy 9, 1915-1916, (2 folders) (Box 22)
    - Sundays
      Note on Sunday Morning meetings
      The Sunday morning meetings were attended by Dr. and Mrs. Cabot, Professor and Mrs. Hocking, Frances Rousmanière (Dewing), Henry Copley Greene, Juliet Pottle, and others.
      - "Sundays" notebook and inserts, 1904-1905 (Box Box 17)
      - Notes on Sunday meetings and other topics and inserts1903-1904 (Box Box 17)
      - Notes on Sunday meetings, "Condemnation", "Apology", "Charity"1905 (Box Box 17)
      - Notes on Sunday meetings, "The Prophet", "The Subconscious", "Reserve", "Happiness", ["Judgment"], letter to ELC from Frances Rousmanière; questions re. beauty; "On Getting the Most Out of Oneself"; "Doubt"1906 (Box Box 17)
      - Notes on Sunday meetings, "Philanthropic Advertising", "Standards in Politics", "The Commonplace", "The Place of Philosophers in the Community", "Immortality and Time"; notes on "discussion", "dissent and agreement"1906 (Box Box 17)
      - "Values" (Box Box 17)
    - Music
      - Dr. Cabot's musical compositions (Box Box 18)
      - Souvenir album presented by "The Christmas Carol Chorus"
      - Musical transcriptions, list of scores
        (Removed from back cover of Souvenir album)
      - Photograph of chorus
        (Removed from front cover of Souvenir album)
      - Christmas singers, 1929-1940 (Box 19)
      - Christmas Chorus music (Box 19)
    - Material donated by Alice O'Gorman, June 1956
      - Autobiographical notes (Box 19)
      - Notes on Creation including bibliographic references, (2 folders) (Box 19)
      - Correspondence re: will, (2 folders) (Box 19)
        Includes correspondence re: Clause III of will which concerns the "Creation Papers."
      - Letters of condolence (Box 20)
        Includes some later letters by friends of Dr. Cabot.
      - O'Gorman notebooks, (13 notebooks) (Box 23)
        Written in shorthand.
    - Publications
      - Reviews of Honesty, May 1938 (Box 21)
      - Reviews of The Art of Ministering to the Sick (Box 21)
      - Reviews of Christianity Sex (Box 21)
      - Publishers lists, lists of names and correspondence (Box 21)
      - Publisher's lists (Box 25)
      - Illustrations used in Creation, 1938-1939 (Box 24)
        Related illustrations filed with lecture notes on course on Creation.
      - Cabot's notes on What Men Live By (Box 24)
    - Teaching Cases
      - 3rd year teaching cases, (2 folders) (Box 24)
      - MGH, 3rd year teaching cases (Box 24)
      - Brigham teaching cases, (2 folders) (Box 24)
      - Cases with Ella Lyman Cabot notes, (2 folders) (Box 25)
      - Child Labor Cases -ELC (Box 22)
    - Miscellanea
      - Text of Letters of E. T. Cabot (Box Box 12)
      - Plays given by Cabot family (Box Boxes 12-13)
      - Notes by unknown writers (Box Box 13)
      - Commemoration of the founding of Medical Social Services (50th Anniversary) (Box 21)
      - ELC Trust Pamphlets (Box 22)
  - Correspondence
    - Correspondence between Richard C. Cabot and Ella Lyman Cabot, 1888-1934
      - Copies of correspondence between Richard C. Cabot and Ella Lyman Cabot, 1888-1934 (Boxes 26-27)
      - Ella Lyman Cabot to Richard C. Cabot, 1888-1899 (originals) (Box Box 30)
      - Ella Lyman Cabot to Richard C. Cabot, 1900-1918, including some photographs (originals) (Box Box 31)
      - Ella Lyman Cabot to Richard C. Cabot, 1918-1934 (originals) (Box Box 32)
    - Ella Lyman Cabot to Mrs. J. Elliott Cabot, 1890-1901 and undated (originals) (Box Box 33)
    - Correspondence between Richard Clarke Cabot/Ella Lyman Cabot and Eleanor C. Slater (originals). (Box Box 28)
    - Richard C. Cabot to various correspondents (Box 29)
      Chronological
      - 1886:
        - "Bess", 1886, 1887
        - "Fan," Miss Frances G. Curtis Rev. Mr. Brown
        - "Uncle Edmund" Dwight
      - 1892:
        - John F. Moors re: E. T. Cabot
        - Miss Mea Coolidge
      - 1896:
        - Mrs. J. Elliot Cabot, 1896-1900
      - 1898:
        - Quotation from A. T. Mahan in R.C.C.'s handwriting.
      - 1901:
        - Mrs. Arthur Lyman; and one from Mrs. Lyman to a Miss O'Gorman
      - 1902:
        - ? re: teaching at Harvard
        - Mrs. Emerson
        - ? from Chicago
        - Frances Rousmanière Dewing (Mrs. Arthur S.), 1902-1934.
      - 1906:
        Missing at time of re-processing, 1975
        - Hammond V. Hayes
        - Dickinson Miller
      - 1908:
        - Philip Cabot, re: will
      - 1911:
        - Dr. E. A. Codman
        - Helen Keller
        - Trustees, Boston Consumptives Hospital Dept.
        - Hon. Henry C. Mulligan, Chairman of Committee on Metropolitan Affairs, State House, Boston.
        - Circular letter re: venereal disease
        - Miss Lucy Hogan, 1911-1938
      - 1912:
        - Miss L. N. Harndon [copied]
        - Hon. John F. Fitzgerald
      - 1913:
        - Dr. Charles Stockton, 1913, 1914
        - Dr. Edward L. Keyes
      - 1914:
        - Miss Ethel W. Chase, 1914-1935
        - Miss Miriam L. Davison, 1914-1938
      - 1915:
        - Dr. F. A. Washburn, re: clinico-pathological records
        - Dr. Arnold
        - Dr. Creighton, re: publication of papers in honor of Josiah Royce
      - 1916:
        - Miss Julia Heyl
        - Dr. Mabel Ulrich
      - 1917:
        - Mr. Ellsworth
        - Miss Lucy Stockton ("Old Lady")
        - ? from Bordeaux, France, re: war handicapped
      - 1921:
        - Paul Kellogg
        - Mrs. Juliet Pottle
      - 1922:
        - Miss Katherine D. Hardwick
        - Dr. Carl Binger
        - Dr. Louis Mendelsohn
        - Interview given to Arthur Gleason
      - 1923:
        - Joseph Lee
      - 1924:
        - Mrs. Henry Copley Greene ("Rosalind")
        - Mrs. Hallowell Davis (Pauline Allen), 1924-1932
      - 1926:
        - Nannie and Basil de Selincourt
      - 1929:
        - Miss Francesca Copley Greene
      - 1930:
        - Miss Claflin (social work)
        - Miss Mary P. Follett
      - 1935:
        - Mrs. Harry Solomon (social work)
      - 1936:
        - Miss Catherine I. Fraser
      - 1937:
        - Miss Wells
        - Dr. Alter
        - Mrs. Amory ("Louise")
      - 1939:
        - Harriett M. Bartlett (social work)
        - Clarence J. Hicks
    - Letters of Ella Lyman Cabot to various friends: (Box Box 34)
      - Mrs. Jaime de Samper (Doris Baldwin)
      - Miss Eleanor C. Slater
      - Miss Lucy Wright
      - Miss Edith Storer
      - Miss Margaret P. Montague
      - Mrs. Charles F. Whiting
      - Dr. Charles G. Stockton
      - Mr. Mrs. Francis B. Duveneck
      - Mrs. John F. Moors (Ethel Paine)
      - Miss Katharine Taylor
      - Mrs. Hamlin Hunt (Mrs. Seth Hunt)
      - Mrs. Fayette Dow (Margaret Elder)
      - Mr. Horace Rigg
      - Mrs. Arthur S. Dewing
      - Miss Lilace Barnes
      - Dr. and Mrs. Hallowell Davis (Pauline Allen)
      - Mrs. Philip Young
      - Sister Maria
      - Mme. Georges Getting
      - Mrs. Fiske Warren
      - Mr. Ivan Lovich
      - Mme. Nicati de Luze
      - Miss Anna Kimball
      - Mrs. Charles Eliot (Mary Eliot)
      - Mrs. Walter Lovell
      - Miss Viola Bryant
    - General Correspondence
      - A-B (Box Box 35)
        Correspondents
        Adams, Gladys
        Adams, Lewis
        "Admirer"
        Agassiz, Lizzie C.
        Allan, Major William (and members of North Carolina Unit, A.E.F.)
        Allen, William H.
        Almy, Helen Cabot (3)
        American Committee... for the Freedom of Mooney and Billings
        American Foundation for the Blind
        American Unitarian Association, per L. C. Cornish, and copy of answer
        Amory, Anna Sears
        Amory, Louise
        Anderson, Mrs. Laura
        Ashford, Bailey K.
        Athenaeum, London, guest membership, 1936
        Atkinson, Edward (re Mrs. Helen Campbell)
        Baker, Mary Olive (5)
        Bakewell, Charles M.
        Baldwin, Anna (2)
        Baldwin, Drusilla
        Baldwin, Roger; American Civil Liberties Union, with copy of answer
        Ball, Ellen Lee (5)
        Barney, Charles Norton
        Barrett, Miss Eileen
        Bartlett, Alice Moulton (5)
        Bartlett, Harriett N.
        Bartol, Lotty (2)
        Beach, S. C. (re Brookline Church, 1887)
        Beatty, Mary E. (5)
        Beaux, Cecilia (5)
        Bent, Janet Woodworth
        Bigby, Margaret H.
        Bittner, Christine (3, and enclosed letter from Tokyo)
        Blanchard, Dr. F. R.
        Boison, Anton T. (re The Meaning of Right and Wrong)
        Bosanquet, Helen and Bernard
        Boycott, Dr. A. E.
        Boyer, E. W.
        Boynton, Richard W.
        Bowditch, Dr. Vincent Y. (2)
        Bowman, Jennie W. (3)
        Braschwitz, Richard
        Bradley, Florence (several)
        Bradley, Miranda (several)
        Breig, Joseph A. (re Christianity and Sex, 1938)
        Brewster, Dr. G. W. W.
        Briggs, George W. (re Brookline Church)
        British Medical Journal, editor
        Brooks, S. (re Brookline Church)
        Brooks, Phillips
        Brown, Anna L.
        Brown, Hillyer
        Brown, Rev. Howard N.
        Brown, Philip King (many letters)
        Brown, Mrs. Philip King (many letters)
        Brush, George deForest
        Bullard, E. L.
        Bullard, Katherine Eliot (2)
        Bullard, Louisa N.
        Bullard, Mary L. (3)
        Bunce, Mary C.
        Burchenal, Elizabeth
        Burdon, Phyllis
        Burke, Virginia R.
        Burleigh, Edith (3)
        Burleigh, Gertrude (2)
        Burr, Allston
        Burton, Flora (re: Tewksbury Almshouse, with copy of reply)
        Bush, Robert W.
      - C (Box Box 36)
        Cabot, Arthur T.
        Cabot, Charles M. (several)
        Cabot, Edward T.
        Cabot, Eliot (6, and 3 from his physicians)
        Cabot, Mrs. F. E.
        Cabot, Godfrey (2)
        Cabot, Mr. and Mrs. Handasyd (2)
        Cabot, Henry B. (2)
        Cabot, Hugh
        Cabot, J. Elliot
        Cabot, L. P. (New Zealand)
        Cabot, Lucy
        Cabot, Mabel
        Cabot, Margaret (Mrs. Joseph Lee, 4)
        Cabot, Mary R.
        Cabot, May Caroline
        Cabot, Nancy (Mrs. Maurice Osborne)
        Cabot, Philip
        Cabot, Ruth
        Cabot, Stephen C.
        Cabot, Walter (several)
        Caldwell, Louise S.
        Calkins, Mary W.
        Campbell, Mrs. C. MacFie
        Campbell, Helen (3)
        Cannon, Antoinette
        Cannon, Ida M. (11)
        Cannon, Dr. Walter B.
        Capps, Joseph A., M. D.
        Carlisle, Dr. G. L.
        Carroll, Bertha
        Cary, Austin (2)
        Channing, Grace Ellery (poem, 1917)
        Chapman, John J.
        Chapman, Mrs. William (3)
        Chase, Ethel (3)
        Cheesman, Dr. William S.
        Clay, Miss G. E.
        Clement, Margaret